<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux diary on Deimos Hall</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux diary on Deimos Hall</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 16:45:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Fedora Update | The Good And The Bad</title>
      <link>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/my-first-fedora-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 07:11:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/my-first-fedora-update/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/thumbnail?id=1L5r6yyV1XYMTXDklfKR61wUFasBQp9db&amp;sz=w1920-h1080&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many times I tried to use a Linux distro as my main OS in the past, but this is the first time it lasted long enough to allow me to do the transition between major versions. In fact, this is also my first time using Fedora as my daily driver, so my experience with this process has been only with this distro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out about the new Fedora 43 release on Twitter and I was excited to update, but at the same time I was expecting bugs to happen, so I waited a couple of days before making the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextcloud, strange feelings</title>
      <link>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/nextcloud-strange-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 19:09:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/nextcloud-strange-feelings/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/thumbnail?id=1JGZk_2rIUKOkqqxHXI85eZQfVPi0qL1o&amp;sz=w1920-h1080&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;I stopped using Nextcloud a couple of days ago because I broke my home server, and I realized I don&amp;rsquo;t miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself using more frequently the local data I have on my PC rather than the one on Nextcloud, the only useful case was for watching some anime chapters on my tablet, but even that could change in the future if I start using &lt;a href=&#34;https://jellyfin.org/&#34;&gt;Jellyfin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I tried to use some of the office integrations that Nextcloud offers, I failed. It was hard to figure out what should I do, I even ended watching tutorials for something I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m a technical person, but the UX is just not intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No more HDDs for me</title>
      <link>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/no-more-hdds-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 18:09:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/no-more-hdds-for-me/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/thumbnail?id=1iD3-Dqkx4Je0dIgHCsxqB1XhR8PAIw6e&amp;sz=w1920-h1080&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;I started my self hosting journey a while ago using an old laptop with Debian 12. It was fine with the internal SSD for a while, but I rapidly had to buy more storage, and I chose a 4 TB external HDD for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t use the HDD for much time, in fact it has damaged sectors, but fortunately I didn&amp;rsquo;t loose any data. The funniest part is I should have suspected of it since the beginning, because I was unable to format it using EXT4 neither on my desktop or laptop. To deal with that issue, I had to format it using BTRFS, it worked, yeah, but now I think the reason of why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to format it using EXT4 could be because of the damaged sectors, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it in that moment. Maybe it was damaged on shipping, who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUTO Keyboard, first impressions</title>
      <link>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/futo-keyboard-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 09:08:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimoshall.dev/blog/linux-diary/2025/futo-keyboard-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/thumbnail?id=12DZHCJYs3MWqF6KrgR7e_sbcCC513kDV&amp;sz=w1083-h609&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using FUTO keyboard since three days ago, I wanted to write about it since day one to consider it as a real first impressions, but I had no time for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, there are things I like and I don&amp;rsquo;t, but in general I could say it is good enough to consider using it as my daily keyboard for more days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-like&#34;&gt;
  What I like
  &lt;a href=&#34;#what-i-like&#34; class=&#34;h-anchor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me start with what I like. It&amp;rsquo;s an open source project with a focus on privacy, and only for that I truly believe it&amp;rsquo;s worth to try it.&lt;/p&gt;
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>